# **Dylan LaMott**

Experienced Remote Software developer with a strong focus in the Java programming language. My current role is a, Java Software Developer, responsible for creating and maintaining applications that automate the provisioning of users for a competitive company.

**Contact information** 

Phone: 336-287-0002

Portfolio website:

https://portfolio-dlamott.vercel.app/

GitHub:

https://github.com/DLaMott

LinkedIn:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/dylan-lamott-b39b472 00/

Skills: Java, Python, Go, AWS, JavaScript, MySQL, SQLite, Kubernetes, HTML, CSS, Terraform, Apache, Windows OS, Mac OS, Linux, Docker, Spring, Jira, Agile Development, DynaTrace, Splunk

**Guilford Technical Community College** 

Jamestown, NC 2020 – 2022

Location: Advance, NC

A.S. Computer Programming

GPA: 4.0

Certifications
Test Out PC Pro

8/20

**Certified by: Test Out** 

Java

December 10, 2021

**Certified by: Guilford Technical community college** 

**Computer Tech Integration** 

May 07, 2021

Certified by: Guilford Technical community college

#### Education

## **Open-source contributions:**

**QuestDB:** An open source database used by Yahoo, TQS, Turk telecom, and more. Find the company website here: <a href="https://questdb.io/">https://questdb.io/</a>

**QuestDB Contribution 1:** Link to accepted and merged PR: <a href="https://github.com/questdb/questdb/pull/1909">https://github.com/questdb/pull/1909</a>

• The resolved issue was to fix long numeric overflow when utilizing nanoseconds to determine thread latch wait time. Previous code had incorrect method usage and incorrect data comparison.

**QuestDB Contribution 2:** Link to accepted and merged PR: <a href="https://github.com/questdb/questdb/pull/1998">https://github.com/questdb/pull/1998</a>

- QuestDB needed a method to track property keys for server configuration files at start-up. Upon taking this issue, I realized the current method to load these property keys was using string literals. Over three hundred lines had lengthy string literal property keys which can be vulnerable to error.
- To promote code reusability, type safety, and reduce errors I created an enum storing property keys. Using my new enum I was able to replace the majority of the code within their server configuration driver.
- I added a test and property key validation method. The added method prevents the server from running if users enter incorrect keys in the server configuration file. The method will throw a server configuration exception and display the invalid line. Overall, this project was merged with QuestDB with 724 added lines

**Projects:** For more projects please view my portfolio website and or my github. My website covers my learning experience and showcases how I solved these projects.

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

## IAM Software engineer, Northwestern Mutual

Remote • May 2022 - Present

- Created a springboot microservice responsible for the provisioning of over 30,000+ users. The microservice is built utilizing
  java and maintains user provisioning by receiving updates on users throughout rest api endpoints within a secure server.
  The microservice maintains a secure AWS Aurora database following microservices best practices. Additionally the MS
  serves as a gateway for a source of truth for Sailpoint IIQ.
- Created four apache kafka consumer microservices to process and manage kafka business events allowing put and post requests towards a provisioning microservice. This allowed the business to move away from legacy applications that utilized MQ services.
- Assisted in creating ideal CI/CD pipelines allowing automated build, code quality scanning, and deployments to test, qa, and production environments.
- Became the acting DevOps Practitioner as well as the primary Java developer for our team.
- Currently leading the DevOps mindset for the IAM team offering support and aid when closing security vulnerabilities found
  on containers, aws instances, applications, and more.
- Created workflows for NM's sailpoint IIQ to enable user provisioning.
- Became an SME for multiple applications in the provisioning space to not only take ownership but also offer support per incidents and knowledge transfers.
- Created a solution as there was not a Restful solution for pulling user information from ED and AD directories. I created a
  springboot ms that handles requests for returning user information by binding utilizing LDAP connections to the
  directories. This MS design and implementation was led by me and now has over 50 teams using the application in all
  environments.
- Created a slackbot used by all applications in the team to provide alerts and create SNOW incidents based on set conditions per each application.
- Enrolled in the AWS developer and cloud practitioner programs as being the front DevOps support member on the team, I also have become the AWS lead for the team.
- Technologies used: AWS, Apache, Spring, Docker, Terraform, Node.js, Kubernetes, Java, Git, Gitlab, Gradle, Cyberark, MSK, Kafka, Kevlar, Cucumber, Dynatrace, Sailpoint, Splunk, Slack, kibana, and SNOW.

## **Production Planner 1, Brakebush**

Remote • January 2020 — May 2022

- Maintained product inventories and analyzed sale data to decide business needs.
- Worked with upper management and team to plan production for three facilities in the USA.
- Worked with logistics, procurement, and sales to manage product inventories and better plan production schedules.

### **Production Lead, Brakebush**

Remote • August 2019 — January 2020

- Lead over 80 plus employees.
- Created and followed daily business plans.
- Ensured proper data recording in infinity and SAP applications.